INFRASTRUCTURE ENGINEER · SECURITY ENTHUSIAS

United States

■ overleaf@winful.com | 😭 www.winful.com | 🖸 swinful | 🛅 samuelawinful

"God uses you wherever you are. And where you are is your ministry." -William H. Myers

Summary

Co-founder & Technologist for two start up companies, Wellness Direct and LeafMatrix LLC. Over a decade leading various large scale projects within the financial industry. A well-rounded technologist. Focused on resilient design and performance, whether in the corporate cloud or on premise. Murex MX.3 and Numerix F3Platform (formally FinCAD) Technology Infrastructure Architect. Unix Systems Administrator. Crypto Blockchain enthusiast. Atypical geek with a high affinity for Vim, Unix/Linux and OS X.

Love to contribute by sharing knowledge and experience and excels at command line interface environments. Highly efficient with tmux, Vim, Unix/Linux, and macOS. Continually learning and problem solving and enjoying the best technology has to offer.

Work Experience

Bank of New York Mellon

New York, NY

SVP, Infrastructure Architect May. 2016 - PRESENT

LeafMatrix LLC Cedar Grove, NJ

FOUNDING MEMBER & SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER & INFRASTRUCTURE TEAM LEAD

Jan. 2023 - PRESENT

Wellness Direct LLC Cedar Grove, NJ

MANAGING MEMBER & CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

Jun. 2019 - PRESENT

Murex North America New York, NY

SR. MX.3 Environment & Configuration Manager

Oct. 2011 - May 2016

Murex North America New York, NY

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER Jun. 2005 - Oct. 2011

L-3 Titan FAA Airforce base, Pomona, NJ

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan. 2005 - Jun. 2005

Danggeun Pay Inc. (KarrotPay)

Seoul, S.Korea

FOUNDING MEMBER & SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER & INFRASTRUCTURE TEAM LEAD

Mar. 2021 - Jun. 2023

- Everything that matters.
- Designed and provisioned the entire infrastructure on the AWS cloud to meet security compliance and acquire a business license for financial services in Korea.
- Continuously improved the infrastructure architecture since launching the service. (currently 3.6 million users)
- Established a standardized base for declarative management of infrastructures and service deployments, enabling operational efficiency and consistency. Over 90% of AWS resources were all managed through standardized terraform modules. All add-ons and service workloads on the Kubernetes cluster were managed on a GitOps basis with Kustomize and ArgoCD.
- Saved over 30% of the overall AWS costs by establishing a quarterly purchasing strategiy for RI (Reserved Instance) and SP (Savings Plan) and by introducing Graviton instances.
- Established a core architecture for regulating of outbound DNS traffic in multi-account and multi-VPC environments utilizing AWS Route53 DNS Firewall and FMS. This significantly increased the level of security confidence in the financial sector's segregated environment.
- Introduced Okta employee identity solution in the company, establishing security policies and configuring SSO integration with over 20 enterprise systems including AWS, GitHub, Slack, Google Workspace. Set up a Hub and Spoke architecture, enabling a collaborative account structure with the parent company, Daangn Market.

Education

New Jersey Institute of Technology

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND BUSINESS

Newark, NJ May. 2015

Rowan University

Glassboro, NJ

May. 2005

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Certificates

2022 Blockchain Essentials - Specialty, eCornell University